Md. Meher Ullah, PHP Developer

Dhaka, Bangladesh, +880 1915 151 681, meherullah97@gmail.com

Nationality	Bangladeshi		
LINKS	Linkedin, GitHub, Article (Medium.com)		
PROFILE	Software Developer with 1+ years of remote job experience. Write code for Infrastructure. Enjoy writing about software, system design, and experience in REST API development, web service, and API integration with 3rd party systems. Committed to utilizing my skills to further the mission of a company.		
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Mar 2022 — Present	PHP Developer, @Wipro (Grame	eenphone Project)	Dhaka(Client Location)
	Try to collaborate with awesome team members on assigned tasks. Show my ability of mine like maintain, coordinate, develop, database design, RESTFull services, and create and maintain the documentation.		
	Technologies used:		
Apr 2019 — Feb 2022	Software Developer, @SCT Technology GmbH.		
	My primary function is to inherit, rebuild, maintain and further develop different endpoints exposing a lot of different use-cases.		
	Technologies used: • PHP (CodeIgniter, Laravel) • Others (Kendo.ui, REST API, Swa • Serves (VPS, cPanel), Angular.js • HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwin		
Feb 2017 — Mar 2019	Full-Stack Web Developer, @Bangladesh Software Development (BSD)		
	My role is to the analysis of product features, design the database, write code for the back-end, and style the front-end components that meet the requirements of user stories.		
	Technologies used:		
EDUCATION			
Oct 2019 — Oct 2022	B.Sc, Northern University of Bangladesh		Dhaka
Oct 2012 — Aug 2016	Diploma in Computer Technology, Jhenaidah Polytechnic Institute Jhenaidah Polytechnic Institute		te Jhenaidah
SKILLS	РНР	ООР	
	CakePHP	jQuery	
	Laravel	Docker	
	Codeigniter	AWS	
	Git	Server(Nginx, Apache	e)
			,

Domain (DNS)

MySQL

JavaScript

Agile Development (Scrum, Kanban

REST API, OPEN API

(Swagger)

HTML & CSS, Bootstrap

Linux

LANGUAGES English Highly proficient Bengali Native speaker